

## Chaitanya Suvarna Developer

- **?** Thane, India
- in LinkedIn
- k chaitanya-suvarna.github.io

## **Profile**

Experienced developer and a strong business development professional with a **Master's Degree** focused in **Computer Applications** from Sardar Patel Institute of Technology.

I am a logical thinker and like solving problems by leveraging technology. I have worked on and delivered ETL based solutions, .NET Web application and Microservices developed with .NET framework.

Being an autodidact, I'm always inquisitive about new technology and trying out various pet projects. Never shying away from opportunities in different technical landscapes.

## **Professional Experience**

## **Barclays**

Developer

07/2017 – present | Pune, India

- .Net developer for Barclays Partner Finances, developing **microservices** using .Net Core WebAPI.
- Developed and delivered **ETL Solution** for Customer Data and Regulatory projects in Ab Initio.
- Developed and delivered **Web Application** in ASP.NET MVC/SQL Server and SSIS for FATCA/CRS Report generation.
- Engaged in various other compliance activities such as AccessControlList feeds, Data remediation and data archival & housekeeping etc.
- Engaged in **change management** and support in various phases of application lifecycle.
- Technologies worked on: .Net Core, Web API, Ab Initio, SQL Server Integration services, SQL Server, ASP.NET,
   Powershell scripting, UNIX shell scripting, ORACLE.

## **Barclays**

01/2017 - 07/2017 | Pune, India

Intern Analyst

- Intern in Legal run the bank team where I provided support for applications used by the Legal team.
- As an intern I developed 2 projects that helped the Legal RTB team perform their support duties efficiently.
  - One-click Health Check of all services/Applications
     Created an executable using C# & Selenium which when executed, all the health check actions were done automatically and an Excel Workbook was generated with status report of all applications.
  - One Stop Shop Service Management

A web application developed with ASP.Net,Bootstrap and SQL Server which used 'Windows Management Instrumentation' to list down all storage/service status of servers being monitored, highlighting stopped services or storage thresholds. You could also start/stop services from the web application.

## **Credit Suisse**

06/2016 - 07/2016 | Pune, India

Intern

- Intern in automation testing team, worked on test case automation using Selenium and Hexawise.
- Got to learn testing concepts like test coverage and how we could leverage these tools to save time and manual effort by automating regression packs etc.

## **Education**

## Sardar Patel Institute of Technology ☐

Master of Computer Applications

Final CGPI: **8.21**/10 Activities and societies:

- Chairperson, ACE Committee
- Student Member, Entrepreneurship Cell

## Usha Pravin Gandhi College of Management 🛭

B.Sc. Information Technology

Final CGPA: **6.80**/8 Activities and societies:

• Mentorship program

• Guitarist, College music group

07/2014 – 07/2017 | Mumbai, India

07/2011 - 07/2014 | Mumbai, India

#### Skills

Ab Initio •

Graph Development, Sandbox Setup, Multifile components, Web Components

SQL Server • • • • •

SQL Server 2012, SQL Server Integration Services

**Agile/Scrum Dev Tools** 

Git, Jira, Rally

Java

Spring Framework, Gradle, JUnit

.Net Framework

.Net Core, ASP.Net, EntityFramework, Web API, Windows Services, NUnit, SpecFlow

Oracle

DDL and DML operations, PL\SQL

**Python** 

Django framework, Beautiful Soup

Web & Javascript

HTML5, CSS3, Javascript, Node.js

08/02/2018

0 0

0 0 0

## **Publications**

# Efficient heart disease prediction system using optimization technique $\ \square$

IEEE Xplore

This research paper focuses on developing a prediction algorithm with the help of data mining and an optimisation technique called Particle Swarm Optimisation technique. The results obtained show that Particle Swarm Data Mining Algorithms are competitive, not only with other evolutionary techniques but also with industry standard algorithms, and can be successfully applied to heart disease prediction.

0 0 0

## **Interests**

## Running

Sub 1 hour 10k finisher. Training for first half marathon.

## Reading

Like reading novels about mystery, mythology, philosophy and history

## **Guitar**

Was part of college music group, still continue playing as a hobby.

## Calligraphy

A hobby that helps me calm down and collect my thoughts.

## Tech/Gadgets 2

Always tinkering with new technology and gadgets with pet projects

## Languages

• English • Hindi

Marathi

Kannada